<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alzheimer&#39;s Disease on swatalla</title>
    <link>https://swatalla.github.io/tags/alzheimers-disease/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alzheimer&#39;s Disease on swatalla</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://swatalla.github.io/tags/alzheimers-disease/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Pain Reports and Brain Activation Patterns in People with Alzheimer&#39;s Disease</title>
      <link>https://swatalla.github.io/project/pain_rep_brain_act/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swatalla.github.io/project/pain_rep_brain_act/</guid>
      <description>NIH/NIA (1K23AG046379-01A1) - $681,000
Continuation of &amp;ldquo;Psychophysical and Neurophysiological Response to Experimental Thermal Pain in Communicative People with Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Disease&amp;rdquo; using modified fMRI paradigms and updated analysis techniques, including resting state functional connectivity, task-evoked functional connectivity, and standard task data analysis modes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychophysical and Neurophysiological Response to Experimental Pain in Communicative Women with Alzheimer’s Disease</title>
      <link>https://swatalla.github.io/project/psych_neur_comm_women/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swatalla.github.io/project/psych_neur_comm_women/</guid>
      <description>American Academy of Nursing/BAGNC, May Day Fund - $5,000
The goal of this comparative group study is to examine how sensory and affective components of pain in women with Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease are psychophysically and neurophysiologically associated, as compared to matched controls. The proposed study will also examine associations relative to AD severity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychophysical and Neurophysiological Response to Experimental Thermal Pain in Communicative People with Alzheimer&#39;s Disease</title>
      <link>https://swatalla.github.io/project/psych_neur_comm_all/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swatalla.github.io/project/psych_neur_comm_all/</guid>
      <description>Vanderbilt VICTR (KL2) - $450,000
Examining the psychophysical and neurophysiological response to pain stimuli in communicative patients with Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease. Using fMRI analysis, we are able to determine regions of activation that correspond to the thermal pain we apply to participants while they undergo a 3T fMRI. The fMRI procedure is coupled with psychophysics and various questionnaires to determine affect, potential for depression, and overall pain experienced by the participant</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>